{
  "language": "Visaya",
  "flashcards": [
    {
      "topic": "Emotions",
      "cards": [
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 1,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "Happy",
              "back": "malipayon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Sad",
              "back": "kasubo"
            },
            {
              "front": "Angry",
              "back": "nasuko"
            },
            {
              "front": "Excited",
              "back": "naghinam-hinam"
            },
            {
              "front": "Nervous",
              "back": "gikulbaan"
            },
            {
              "front": "Scared",
              "back": "nahadlok"
            },
            {
              "front": "Calm",
              "back": "kalmado"
            },
            {
              "front": "Confused",
              "back": "naglibog"
            },
            {
              "front": "Anxious",
              "back": "nabalaka"
            },
            {
              "front": "Surprised",
              "back": "natingala"
            },
            {
              "front": "Frustrated",
              "back": "nahigawad"
            },
            {
              "front": "Embarrassed",
              "back": "naulaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "Jealous",
              "back": "selos"
            },
            {
              "front": "Grateful",
              "back": "mapasalamaton"
            },
            {
              "front": "Proud",
              "back": "mapahitas-on"
            },
            {
              "front": "Curious",
              "back": "kahibaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "Lonely",
              "back": "kamingaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "Tired",
              "back": "gikapoy"
            },
            {
              "front": "Relaxed",
              "back": "nagpahayahay"
            },
            {
              "front": "Hopeful",
              "back": "malaumon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Bored",
              "back": "laay"
            },
            {
              "front": "Shocked",
              "back": "nakurat"
            },
            {
              "front": "Guilty",
              "back": "sad-an"
            },
            {
              "front": "Confident",
              "back": "masaligon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Ashamed",
              "back": "maulaw"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 2,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "Jealous man",
              "back": "tawo nga seloso"
            },
            {
              "front": "Surprised cat",
              "back": "natingala nga iring"
            },
            {
              "front": "Anxious boy",
              "back": "nabalaka nga batang lalaki"
            },
            {
              "front": "Calm captain",
              "back": "kalmado nga kapitan"
            },
            {
              "front": "Nervous performer",
              "back": "nerbiyos nga performer"
            },
            {
              "front": "Excited child",
              "back": "excited nga bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "Tired worker",
              "back": "gikapoy nga trabahante"
            },
            {
              "front": "Angry driver",
              "back": "suko nga drayber"
            },
            {
              "front": "Happy friend",
              "back": "malipayon nga higala"
            },
            {
              "front": "Sad dog",
              "back": "iro sad"
            },
            {
              "front": "Relaxed tourist",
              "back": "relaks nga turista"
            },
            {
              "front": "Lonely artist",
              "back": "mingaw nga artista"
            },
            {
              "front": "Grateful student",
              "back": "mapasalamaton nga estudyante"
            },
            {
              "front": "Confused traveler",
              "back": "naglibog nga biyahedor"
            },
            {
              "front": "Scared child",
              "back": "nahadlok nga bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "Hopeful teacher",
              "back": "malaumon nga magtutudlo"
            },
            {
              "front": "Frustrated athlete",
              "back": "napakyas nga atleta"
            },
            {
              "front": "Curious scientist",
              "back": "kuryuso nga siyentista"
            },
            {
              "front": "Embarrassed speaker",
              "back": "maulaw nga mamumulong"
            },
            {
              "front": "Proud parent",
              "back": "garboso nga ginikanan"
            },
            {
              "front": "Shocked audience",
              "back": "nakurat nga mamiminaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "Bored student",
              "back": "bored nga estudyante"
            },
            {
              "front": "Guilty suspect",
              "back": "guilty nga suspek"
            },
            {
              "front": "Confident leader",
              "back": "masaligon nga lider"
            },
            {
              "front": "Ashamed child",
              "back": "maulaw nga bata"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 3,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I am bored",
              "back": "gikapoy nako"
            },
            {
              "front": "He is nervous",
              "back": "gikulbaan siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "She is excited",
              "back": "excited siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "They are lonely",
              "back": "nag-inusara sila"
            },
            {
              "front": "I feel frustrated",
              "back": "naguol ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "He looks confused",
              "back": "murag naglibog siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "She stays calm",
              "back": "nagpabilin siyang kalmado"
            },
            {
              "front": "They seem anxious",
              "back": "daw nabalaka sila"
            },
            {
              "front": "Sad dog lies",
              "back": "bakak nga iro sad"
            },
            {
              "front": "Angry driver yells",
              "back": "suko nga drayber singgit"
            },
            {
              "front": "Jealous man complains",
              "back": "reklamo sa tawo nga seloso"
            },
            {
              "front": "Calm captain leads",
              "back": "kalmado nga kapitan ang nanguna"
            },
            {
              "front": "Anxious boy fidgets",
              "back": "nabalaka nga batang lalaki nga naglibog"
            },
            {
              "front": "Happy friend laughs",
              "back": "malipayon nga higala mikatawa"
            },
            {
              "front": "Surprised cat jumps",
              "back": "natingala nga iring milukso"
            },
            {
              "front": "Tired worker rests",
              "back": "kapoy nga trabahador nagpahuway"
            },
            {
              "front": "Confident leader speaks",
              "back": "masaligon nga lider nagsulti"
            },
            {
              "front": "Proud parent smiles",
              "back": "mapahitas-on nga ginikanan pahiyom"
            },
            {
              "front": "Curious scientist observes",
              "back": "mausisaon nga siyentista nag-obserbar"
            },
            {
              "front": "Frustrated athlete quits",
              "back": "napakyas nga atleta miundang"
            },
            {
              "front": "Nervous performer shakes",
              "back": "gikulbaan performer uyog"
            },
            {
              "front": "Hopeful teacher teaches",
              "back": "malaumon nga magtutudlo nagtudlo"
            },
            {
              "front": "He feels grateful",
              "back": "siya mibati nga mapasalamaton"
            },
            {
              "front": "She feels guilty",
              "back": "nakonsensya siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "I feel ashamed",
              "back": "naulaw ko"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 4,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I am sad now",
              "back": "naguol ko karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "He is very jealous",
              "back": "selosa kaayo siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "Dogs are happy animals",
              "back": "ang mga iro malipayong mga mananap"
            },
            {
              "front": "The performer is nervous",
              "back": "gikulbaan ang performer"
            },
            {
              "front": "She is very excited",
              "back": "excited kaayo siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "They feel extremely anxious",
              "back": "gibati nila ang hilabihang kabalaka"
            },
            {
              "front": "I am feeling calm",
              "back": "kalma ang akong gibati"
            },
            {
              "front": "He is looking surprised",
              "back": "murag natingala siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "The child feels scared",
              "back": "nahadlok ang bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "We are very proud",
              "back": "proud kaayo mi"
            },
            {
              "front": "My friend seems confused",
              "back": "murag naglibog akong amiga"
            },
            {
              "front": "The audience looks shocked",
              "back": "murag na shock ang audience"
            },
            {
              "front": "The scientist is curious",
              "back": "kahibaw ang siyentista"
            },
            {
              "front": "I am grateful today",
              "back": "mapasalamaton ko karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "She seems very lonely",
              "back": "mura siyag mingaw kaayo"
            },
            {
              "front": "He feels quite relaxed",
              "back": "medyo relaks ang iyang gibati"
            },
            {
              "front": "The athlete is frustrated",
              "back": "ang atleta napakyas"
            },
            {
              "front": "I am really hopeful",
              "back": "malaumon gyud ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "The student feels embarrassed",
              "back": "naulaw ang estudyante"
            },
            {
              "front": "They are feeling tired",
              "back": "gibati nila ang kakapoy"
            },
            {
              "front": "He feels very calm",
              "back": "kalma kaayo ang iyang gibati"
            },
            {
              "front": "She is incredibly confident",
              "back": "dako kaayo siyag pagsalig"
            },
            {
              "front": "My dog looks sad",
              "back": "murag sad akong iro"
            },
            {
              "front": "The child seems anxious",
              "back": "murag nabalaka ang bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "I am very happy",
              "back": "malipayon kaayo ko"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 5,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "She is feeling very hopeful",
              "back": "gibati niya nga malaumon kaayo"
            },
            {
              "front": "My dog looks really happy",
              "back": "murag malipayon kaayo akong iro"
            },
            {
              "front": "The athlete failed the test",
              "back": "ang atleta napakyas sa pagsulay"
            },
            {
              "front": "The boy is anxious today",
              "back": "nabalaka ang bata karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "He is feeling very jealous",
              "back": "selos kaayo siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "I am feeling quite relaxed",
              "back": "medyo relaks ang akong gibati"
            },
            {
              "front": "They are really excited now",
              "back": "excited na gyud sila karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The performer feels very nervous",
              "back": "kulbaan kaayo ang performer"
            },
            {
              "front": "We are feeling very proud",
              "back": "proud kaayo mi"
            },
            {
              "front": "My friend looks really confused",
              "back": "akong amiga murag libog gyud"
            },
            {
              "front": "She is very grateful today",
              "back": "mapasalamaton kaayo siya karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "He feels embarrassed in public",
              "back": "naulaw siya sa publiko"
            },
            {
              "front": "The audience seems really shocked",
              "back": "murag na shock gyud ang audience"
            },
            {
              "front": "The student feels extremely tired",
              "back": "ang estudyante gibati og hilabihan nga kakapoy"
            },
            {
              "front": "The scientist is feeling curious",
              "back": "Gibati sa siyentista nga nakuryoso"
            },
            {
              "front": "I am feeling very calm",
              "back": "kalma kaayo ang akong gibati"
            },
            {
              "front": "She feels incredibly confident today",
              "back": "gibati niya ang dili katuohan nga pagsalig karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "He is feeling quite angry",
              "back": "medyo nasuko siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "My cat seems very curious",
              "back": "murag curious kaayo akong iring"
            },
            {
              "front": "The teacher looks really frustrated",
              "back": "murag frustrated gyud ang maestra"
            },
            {
              "front": "I am feeling really happy",
              "back": "nalipay kaayo ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "The child feels scared today",
              "back": "nahadlok ang bata karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "They are feeling extremely anxious",
              "back": "gibati nila ang hilabihang kabalaka"
            },
            {
              "front": "He feels proud of himself",
              "back": "mapasigarbuhon siya sa iyang kaugalingon"
            },
            {
              "front": "She is very confident today",
              "back": "masaligon kaayo siya karon"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 6,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I am starting to feel nervous",
              "back": "nagsugod na kog kakulba"
            },
            {
              "front": "The boy became happy after school",
              "back": "ang bata nahimong malipayon human sa eskwelahan"
            },
            {
              "front": "The girl felt embarrassed in school",
              "back": "ang babaye mibati og kaulaw sa eskwelahan"
            },
            {
              "front": "My cat makes me feel calm",
              "back": "ang akong iring nagpakalma kanako"
            },
            {
              "front": "She is trying to stay hopeful",
              "back": "naningkamot siya nga magpabiling malaumon"
            },
            {
              "front": "He is feeling very confident today",
              "back": "kompiyansa kaayo siya karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "They are beginning to feel tired",
              "back": "nagsugod na silag kakapoy"
            },
            {
              "front": "I am feeling quite excited now",
              "back": "medyo excited na kaayo ko karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The athlete seems very frustrated today",
              "back": "murag frustrated kaayo ang athlete karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "My dog makes me really happy",
              "back": "ang akong iro nakapalipay kaayo kanako"
            },
            {
              "front": "He is starting to feel anxious",
              "back": "nagsugod na siyag kakulba"
            },
            {
              "front": "She feels proud of her accomplishments",
              "back": "mapasigarbuhon siya sa iyang mga nahimo"
            },
            {
              "front": "We are feeling extremely hopeful today",
              "back": "gibati namo ang hilabihan nga paglaum karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The performer is feeling very nervous",
              "back": "Gikulbaan pag-ayo ang performer"
            },
            {
              "front": "The audience looks shocked and surprised",
              "back": "ang mga tumatan-aw daw natingala ug natingala"
            },
            {
              "front": "My friend seems confused about everything",
              "back": "akong amiga murag libog sa tanan"
            },
            {
              "front": "I am feeling relaxed after the trip",
              "back": "Gibati nako nga relaks pagkahuman sa biyahe"
            },
            {
              "front": "He is trying to stay calm",
              "back": "naningkamot siya nga magpabiling kalmado"
            },
            {
              "front": "She is feeling curious about science",
              "back": "Nakuryoso siya bahin sa siyensya"
            },
            {
              "front": "The teacher feels really proud today",
              "back": "mapasigarbuhon kaayo ang magtutudlo karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "They are feeling very grateful today",
              "back": "mapasalamaton kaayo sila karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The child looks scared of heights",
              "back": "murag nahadlok sa height ang bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "The scientist is feeling quite curious",
              "back": "medyo kuryoso ang gibati sa siyentista"
            },
            {
              "front": "She is starting to feel jealous",
              "back": "nagsugod na siyag selos"
            },
            {
              "front": "He became anxious after the meeting",
              "back": "nabalaka siya pagkahuman sa miting"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 2,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "Was scared",
              "back": "nahadlok"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was happy",
              "back": "malipayon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was grateful",
              "back": "mapasalamaton"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was nervous",
              "back": "gikulbaan"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was excited",
              "back": "naghinam-hinam"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was calm",
              "back": "kalmado"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was anxious",
              "back": "nabalaka"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was curious",
              "back": "nakuryoso"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was sad",
              "back": "naguol"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was surprised",
              "back": "natingala"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was proud",
              "back": "mapasigarbuhon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was embarrassed",
              "back": "naulaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was angry",
              "back": "nasuko"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was jealous",
              "back": "nagselos"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was frustrated",
              "back": "nasagmuyo"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was tired",
              "back": "gikapoy"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was bored",
              "back": "na bored"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was confident",
              "back": "masaligon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was guilty",
              "back": "nakasala"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was hopeful",
              "back": "malaumon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was ashamed",
              "back": "naulaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was relaxed",
              "back": "nagpahayahay"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was lonely",
              "back": "nag-inusara"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was shocked",
              "back": "nakurat"
            },
            {
              "front": "Was confused",
              "back": "naglibog"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 3,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I was angry",
              "back": "nasuko ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was sad",
              "back": "naguol siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were excited",
              "back": "naghinam-hinam sila"
            },
            {
              "front": "Dogs were tired",
              "back": "gikapoy ang mga iro"
            },
            {
              "front": "Captains were confident",
              "back": "masaligon ang mga kapitan"
            },
            {
              "front": "Boys were curious",
              "back": "ang mga lalaki nakuryuso"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was nervous",
              "back": "gikulbaan siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was grateful",
              "back": "mapasalamaton siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "We were happy",
              "back": "malipayon mi"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was embarrassed",
              "back": "naulaw siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were proud",
              "back": "gipasigarbo nila"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was frustrated",
              "back": "nasagmuyo siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "I was relaxed",
              "back": "nagpahayahay ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were lonely",
              "back": "nag-inusara sila"
            },
            {
              "front": "children were surprised",
              "back": "natingala ang mga bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "students were bored",
              "back": "ang mga estudyante gikapoy"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was shocked",
              "back": "nakurat siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "I was scared",
              "back": "nahadlok ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was hopeful",
              "back": "malaumon siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "We were anxious",
              "back": "kami nabalaka"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were jealous",
              "back": "nasina sila"
            },
            {
              "front": "friend was confused",
              "back": "amigo naglibog"
            },
            {
              "front": "team was proud",
              "back": "mapasigarbuhon ang team"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was guilty",
              "back": "nakasala siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "audience was shocked",
              "back": "ang mga mamiminaw nakurat"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 4,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "The boy was very happy",
              "back": "malipayon kaayo ang bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "My dogs were excited",
              "back": "naghinam-hinam ang akong mga iro"
            },
            {
              "front": "They have anxious cats",
              "back": "naa silay gikabalak-an nga mga iring"
            },
            {
              "front": "Our students were bored",
              "back": "nauwaw ang among mga estudyante"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was very nervous",
              "back": "kulbaan kaayo siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "He felt extremely proud",
              "back": "gibati niya ang hilabihang garbo"
            },
            {
              "front": "We were all surprised",
              "back": "natingala ming tanan"
            },
            {
              "front": "The team was confident",
              "back": "ang team masaligon"
            },
            {
              "front": "I was feeling jealous",
              "back": "nagselos ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "My friend was confused",
              "back": "naglibog akong amigo"
            },
            {
              "front": "The audience was shocked",
              "back": "nakurat ang audience"
            },
            {
              "front": "He felt very relaxed",
              "back": "hayahay kaayo ang iyang gibati"
            },
            {
              "front": "The girl was scared",
              "back": "nahadlok ang babaye"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was really excited",
              "back": "excited gyud siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were quite happy",
              "back": "medyo malipayon sila"
            },
            {
              "front": "The athlete was frustrated",
              "back": "ang atleta napakyas"
            },
            {
              "front": "He felt extremely guilty",
              "back": "gibati niya ang hilabihan nga pagkasad-an"
            },
            {
              "front": "The dog was calm",
              "back": "kalmado ang iro"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were really anxious",
              "back": "nabalaka gayod sila"
            },
            {
              "front": "I felt very ashamed",
              "back": "naulaw kaayo ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "We were feeling hopeful",
              "back": "mibati mig paglaom"
            },
            {
              "front": "The child was embarrassed",
              "back": "naulaw ang bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "She felt very grateful",
              "back": "mapasalamaton kaayo siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "The boys were curious",
              "back": "nakuryuso ang mga lalaki"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was very confident",
              "back": "masaligon kaayo siya"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 5,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I am feeling sad today",
              "back": "naguol ko karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Dogs are always happy animals",
              "back": "iro mao ang kanunay nga malipayon nga mga mananap"
            },
            {
              "front": "Cats get nervous when startled",
              "back": "makulbaan ang mga iring kon makurat"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was grateful to him",
              "back": "mapasalamaton siya kaniya"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was ashamed about work",
              "back": "naulaw siya sa trabaho"
            },
            {
              "front": "We were feeling very hopeful",
              "back": "naglaom kaayo mi"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were excited about school",
              "back": "excited na sila sa eskwelahan"
            },
            {
              "front": "He felt extremely proud yesterday",
              "back": "grabe ang iyang garbo kagahapon"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was embarrassed at school",
              "back": "naulaw siya sa eskwelahan"
            },
            {
              "front": "My dog looked really happy",
              "back": "malipayon kaayo akong iro"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was really nervous today",
              "back": "gikulbaan gyud siya karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The audience was very surprised",
              "back": "natingala kaayo ang audience"
            },
            {
              "front": "I was feeling anxious yesterday",
              "back": "Gibati ko ang kabalaka kagahapon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The child felt very scared",
              "back": "gibati og tumang kahadlok ang bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were confused about it",
              "back": "naglibog sila bahin niini"
            },
            {
              "front": "She felt guilty about mistakes",
              "back": "nakonsensya siya sa mga sayop"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was feeling quite lonely",
              "back": "gibati niya nga nag-inusara"
            },
            {
              "front": "My friend was very tired",
              "back": "kapoy kaayo akong amiga"
            },
            {
              "front": "We were proud of ourselves",
              "back": "gipasigarbo namo ang among kaugalingon"
            },
            {
              "front": "She felt calm during tests",
              "back": "gibati niya nga kalmado panahon sa mga pagsulay"
            },
            {
              "front": "The team was very confident",
              "back": "masaligon kaayo ang team"
            },
            {
              "front": "I was ashamed after work",
              "back": "naulaw ko human sa trabaho"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was angry about yesterday",
              "back": "nasuko siya sa kagahapon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The boy felt incredibly anxious",
              "back": "ang bata mibati og tumang kabalaka"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was happy with results",
              "back": "nalipay siya sa mga resulta"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 6,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "Dogs are happy when at home",
              "back": "ang mga iro malipayon kung naa sa balay"
            },
            {
              "front": "Boys are excited when around girls",
              "back": "Ang mga lalaki madasigon kon anaa sa mga babaye"
            },
            {
              "front": "I was ashamed by my mistakes",
              "back": "naulaw ko sa akong mga sayop"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were anxious about the trip",
              "back": "nabalaka sila sa biyahe"
            },
            {
              "front": "The captain was confident at work",
              "back": "masaligon ang kapitan sa trabaho"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was grateful for his help",
              "back": "mapasalamaton siya sa iyang tabang"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was frustrated by the results",
              "back": "nasagmuyo siya sa resulta"
            },
            {
              "front": "We were hopeful about the future",
              "back": "naglaum kami bahin sa umaabot"
            },
            {
              "front": "My dog was happy at home",
              "back": "malipayon ang akong iro sa balay"
            },
            {
              "front": "The students were bored in class",
              "back": "bored ang mga estudyante sa klase"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was proud of his achievement",
              "back": "mapasigarbuhon siya sa iyang nahimo"
            },
            {
              "front": "The child was nervous before school",
              "back": "ang bata gikulbaan sa wala pa ang eskwelahan"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was excited about the party",
              "back": "excited siya sa party"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were confused by the instructions",
              "back": "naglibog sila sa mga instruksyon"
            },
            {
              "front": "I was embarrassed by my actions",
              "back": "naulaw ko sa akong mga binuhatan"
            },
            {
              "front": "The team was confident about the win",
              "back": "ang team masaligon sa kadaugan"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was jealous of her success",
              "back": "nasina siya sa iyang kalampusan"
            },
            {
              "front": "The performer was nervous before performing",
              "back": "gikulbaan ang performer sa wala pa magpasundayag"
            },
            {
              "front": "We were relaxed after the event",
              "back": "nagpahayahay kami pagkahuman sa panghitabo"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was lonely during the trip",
              "back": "nag-inusara siya sa biyahe"
            },
            {
              "front": "He was tired after a long day",
              "back": "gikapoy siya human sa taas nga adlaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "They were shocked by the surprise",
              "back": "nakurat sila sa katingala"
            },
            {
              "front": "I was happy with the results",
              "back": "Nalipay ko sa mga resulta"
            },
            {
              "front": "The boys were curious about science",
              "back": "ang mga lalaki interesado sa siyensya"
            },
            {
              "front": "She was confident during the test",
              "back": "masaligon siya sa panahon sa pagsulay"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "future",
          "wordcount": 3,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "Will be nervous",
              "back": "makulbaan"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be excited",
              "back": "maghinamhinam"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be happy",
              "back": "mahimong malipayon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be scared",
              "back": "mahadlok"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will feel proud",
              "back": "mobati og garbo"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be grateful",
              "back": "mahimong mapasalamaton"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will feel relaxed",
              "back": "mobati nga relaks"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be anxious",
              "back": "mabalaka"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will feel guilty",
              "back": "makonsensya"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be calm",
              "back": "mahimong kalmado"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be jealous",
              "back": "magselos"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be hopeful",
              "back": "mahimong malaumon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be bored",
              "back": "mauwaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will feel confused",
              "back": "mobati og kalibog"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be embarrassed",
              "back": "maulawan"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be shocked",
              "back": "makurat"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be tired",
              "back": "kapoyon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will feel lonely",
              "back": "mobati og kamingaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be angry",
              "back": "masuko"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will feel relaxed",
              "back": "mobati nga relaks"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will feel confident",
              "back": "mobati nga masaligon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will feel frustrated",
              "back": "mobati og kasagmuyo"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be surprised",
              "back": "matingala"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will be calm",
              "back": "mahimong kalmado"
            },
            {
              "front": "Will feel curious",
              "back": "mobati nga kahibaw"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "future",
          "wordcount": 4,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I will be curious",
              "back": "ma curious ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "Dog will become happy",
              "back": "iro mahimong malipayon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Cats will be relaxed",
              "back": "ang mga iring magpahayahay"
            },
            {
              "front": "Fathers will be calm",
              "back": "ang mga amahan mahimong kalmado"
            },
            {
              "front": "Students will be frustrated",
              "back": "ang mga estudyante mapakyas"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will be anxious",
              "back": "siya mabalaka"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will feel proud",
              "back": "mobati siyag garbo"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will be excited",
              "back": "maghinamhinam sila"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will feel grateful",
              "back": "kita mobati nga mapasalamaton"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will be nervous",
              "back": "kulbaan ko"
            },
            {
              "front": "The child will be happy",
              "back": "malipay ang bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "The audience will be shocked",
              "back": "ang mamiminaw makurat"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will be embarrassed",
              "back": "maulaw siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "My friend will be jealous",
              "back": "magselos akong amiga"
            },
            {
              "front": "The dog will feel calm",
              "back": "ang iro mobati nga kalmado"
            },
            {
              "front": "The team will be confident",
              "back": "ang team masaligon"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will be relaxed",
              "back": "siya magpahayahay"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will feel lonely",
              "back": "bation nila ang kamingaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "The boys will feel bored",
              "back": "ang mga lalaki makabati ug kalaay"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will feel tired",
              "back": "makabati kog kakapoy"
            },
            {
              "front": "The girl will feel scared",
              "back": "mahadlok ang babaye"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will feel confused",
              "back": "maglibog siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will be hopeful",
              "back": "kita magmalaumon"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will be guilty",
              "back": "makasala siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will feel ashamed",
              "back": "maulaw sila"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "future",
          "wordcount": 5,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "They will be ashamed soon",
              "back": "maulaw sila dayon"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will become excited soon",
              "back": "maghinamhinam siya sa dili madugay"
            },
            {
              "front": "Dogs will be lonely tomorrow",
              "back": "mamingaw ang mga iro ugma"
            },
            {
              "front": "Birds will excite the cats",
              "back": "ang mga langgam makapahinam sa mga iring"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will be happy tomorrow",
              "back": "malipay ko ugma"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will feel proud soon",
              "back": "mapasigarbuhon siya sa dili madugay"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will become very curious",
              "back": "mausisa kaayo siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "The students will feel frustrated",
              "back": "ang mga estudyante mobati og kasagmuyo"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will feel anxious tomorrow",
              "back": "bation nato ang kabalaka ugma"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will be nervous soon",
              "back": "kulbaan sila dayon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The child will be excited",
              "back": "maghinam-hinam ang bata"
            },
            {
              "front": "My friend will feel guilty",
              "back": "makonsensya akong amigo"
            },
            {
              "front": "The team will be hopeful",
              "back": "malaumon ang team"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will feel very calm",
              "back": "kalmado kaayo siya"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will be jealous soon",
              "back": "magselos ko dayon"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will be lonely tomorrow",
              "back": "mamingaw na siya ugma"
            },
            {
              "front": "The boys will feel ashamed",
              "back": "maulaw ang mga laki"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will be happy soon",
              "back": "malipay ta sa dili madugay"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will feel confused tomorrow",
              "back": "maglibog siya ugma"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will become proud parents",
              "back": "sila mahimong mapahitas-on nga mga ginikanan"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will feel relaxed tomorrow",
              "back": "hayahay na siya ugma"
            },
            {
              "front": "The dog will be tired",
              "back": "kapoyon ang iro"
            },
            {
              "front": "The audience will be shocked",
              "back": "ang mamiminaw makurat"
            },
            {
              "front": "The girls will feel bored",
              "back": "ang mga babaye mobati og kalaay"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will feel confident soon",
              "back": "ako mobati nga masaligon sa dili madugay"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "future",
          "wordcount": 6,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "Balls will make dogs happy today",
              "back": "ang mga bola makapalipay sa mga iro karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "Birds make cats excited outside",
              "back": "ang mga langgam makapahinam sa mga iring sa gawas"
            },
            {
              "front": "Tests will make students very anxious",
              "back": "ang mga pagsulay makapabalaka pag-ayo sa mga estudyante"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will be confident at work",
              "back": "masaligon siya sa trabaho"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will be frustrated at school",
              "back": "madismaya sila sa eskwelahan"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will feel excited tomorrow morning",
              "back": "mabati ko ang kahinam ugma sa buntag"
            },
            {
              "front": "The movie will make them scared",
              "back": "ang salida makapahadlok kanila"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will be proud of herself",
              "back": "ipasigarbo niya ang iyang kaugalingon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The boys will feel nervous soon",
              "back": "kulbaan dayon ang mga laki"
            },
            {
              "front": "My dog will feel happy later",
              "back": "malipay ang akong iro unya"
            },
            {
              "front": "The audience will be shocked tonight",
              "back": "makurat ang mamiminaw karong gabhiona"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will feel grateful for help",
              "back": "siya mobati nga mapasalamaton alang sa tabang"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will be anxious before the test",
              "back": "kita mabalaka sa dili pa ang pagsulay"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will be lonely all day",
              "back": "magmingaw siya tibuok adlaw"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will become excited after school",
              "back": "sila mahimong maghinam-hinam human sa eskwelahan"
            },
            {
              "front": "The athlete will be confident tomorrow",
              "back": "masaligon ang atleta ugma"
            },
            {
              "front": "The teacher will feel proud today",
              "back": "mapasigarbuhon ang magtutudlo karon"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will feel tired after work",
              "back": "siya mobati og kakapoy human sa trabaho"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will feel relaxed after dinner",
              "back": "Mohayahay ko human sa panihapon"
            },
            {
              "front": "The performer will feel nervous backstage",
              "back": "makulbaan ang performer sa backstage"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will be happy with results",
              "back": "malipay ta sa mga resulta"
            },
            {
              "front": "The girls will be bored tomorrow",
              "back": "ang mga babaye mauwaw ugma"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will be jealous of others",
              "back": "magselos siya sa uban"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will be curious about everything",
              "back": "mausisa siya sa tanan"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will be hopeful next week",
              "back": "malaumon sila sunod semana"
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}